

## Wilder Samuel Taborda Cerón

## Career Summary

Wilder Samuel is a developer with 2 years of experience using web technologies such as MERN Stack, His first participation in a huge project was in a loyalty program of Abbott and He has worked and led full stack projects such as an e-commerce website and a social network

## Summary of Qualifications

## Experienced In:

- ReactJS
- NextJS
- NodeJS
- MongoDB
- Redux
- Sass

- Styled-compo
- Python
- Javascript
- Typescript
- ExpressJS
- Axios

# Languages

Spanish (native speaker)

English (advanced)

### Career History

## **GLOBANT, Bogotá, Colombia**

Developer

- Define the layout and the functionality of different pages
- Implementing a node script to generate global data for the app
- Solving bugs to get a clean code
- Refactor the code to avoid bugs

#### Social Network, Bogotá, Colombia

Developer

- Implement cloud services provided by google in the application
- Create the functionalities to share, comment, react and delete
- Adjust the functions created to connect the frontend with the backend
- Stylize the page
- Refactor the code to avoid bugs

#### Mil-corotos, Bogotá, Colombia

Leader

- Lead daily meetings
- Select the technological stack that best suits the skills of the group
- Support the team in the resolution of internal conflicts
- Delegate functionalities and modules to each of the members

## Developer

- Build the API for data handling in the backend
- connect components using redux
- Create the connection to the database
- Solve communication problems between components
- Create the routes to which requests are made from the frontend

Nov. 2020-Jan. 2021

Dec. 2021-Now

Jul. 2021-Sep. 2021



Nov. 2020-Jan. 2021

## Netflix Clone, Bogotá, Colombia

Developer

- Implement google authentication service
- Connection creation and API data handling
- Use the API data to create the components of the movies or series
- Stylize the page

## **Gmail Clone, Bogotá, Colombia**

Jul. 2021-Sep. 2021

Developer

- Create the functional components of the app and connect them to each other
- Implement google authentication service
- Create the requests to the database
- Manage the flow of users throughout the application

#### Education

<b>Universidad Militar Nueva Granada</b> , Bogotá, Colombia BS, Mechatronics Engineering	Jan. 2019 – Jan. 2023
<b>MongoDB University</b> , Bogotá, Colombia MongoDB for JavaScript Developers	Sep. 2021 – Oct. 2021
<b>FreeCodeCamp</b> , Bogotá, Colombia Scientific Computing with Python	Apr. 2021 – May. 2021
<b>Udemy</b> , Bogotá, Colombia React from scratch	Jun. 2021 – Jun. 2021